Albert Abril

Senior Software Engineer / DevOps

A http://www.albertabril.com in linkedin.com/in/albertabril

qithub.com/aabril

// Fluent **English** // Native Spanish Catalan // Native

Key Skills

Languages

· API design and implementation

· Continous Integration

- Microservices
- · Relational and NoSQL databases Test Driven Development
- Web Frontend development Message Queuing

NodeJS

Technical Skills

Javascript / Typescript

- Bash Scripting Docker
- Kubernetes GCP adminisitration Linux Servers

- **Current Learnings**
- · Getting proficient in Go CNCF universe

Want to learn

· Dive into unikraft.org Rust & Haskell

• Played the Oboe as a teen · Worked as a cinema projectionist

Misc

About

devops and continuous integration / continuous delivery. Most of my experience has been working as a full-stack developer

Software engineer with background in backend, microservices,

using NodeJS as a main ecosystem, more with a tendency into backend and architecture. Also worked in other languages as Python and PHP. As a candidate, I am particularly interested in highlighting my

expertise in architecture, dedication to producing well-planned work, and the possibility to apply devops expertise. Cloud Native, concurrent and low level languages has been on my target lately.

Mirage - Topcon Group

Work Experience - Summary

- Funky Data 2019 Vendigo Finance
- Funky Data 2016 Swishd Commonplace.is
- SpottinStyle LaTiendaHome

Bit2Me

- SpottinStyle MVP VICE Magazine
- AdLemons
- Education
- Universitat Oberta de Catalunya // dropped 2006 - 2007 // Enginyeria Tècnica en Telecomunicacions Esp. Telemàtica
- London, UK 2013.01
 - València, Spain 2011.03

London, UK 2019.07

London, UK 2017.09

London, UK 2016.07

Universitat de València // moved to remote 2003 - 2006 // Enginyeria Informàtica (Computer Science)

Awards ResetWeekend 2013

ResetWeekend.org is an startup competition, where contestants propose their ideas, and the community votes for the ideas they feel are the best, then these are developed over the weekend. The concept that

won was a social alarm clock that wakes your relatives up with custom music or music accumstomed to their tastes. We named it PlayMyDay link: https://youtu.be/vwQ8VGuouYw

Work Experience (2023-2011)

Migrate from Drone-Cl to Woodpecker-Cl

Senior Software Engineer /// DevOps

Extract pipelines files from each repo to a central service Support devs with deployment on their scoped services

Bit2Me

Support devs with connection and workflow through services Work hand by hand with sysdamins (later DevOps team too) Support Cybersecurity team to accomplish with ISO-27001

#grafana #prometheus #google-trace

Code Contributions to Core Team

Work on existing legacy Django projects

- Install Google Trace on each service for observability Help to set up tools as Grafana, Sentry and Snyk
- Mirage Topcon Group Software Engineer /// Backend & Infrastructure

Delivers implementations or solutions to different services

#node #typescript #bash #go #docker #docker-compose

#kubernetes #drone-ci #woodpecker-ci #GoogleCloudPlatform

· Structure of the API with django-rest Improve backend services with Python Front load-balancer with NodeJS Lambdas (serverless) Modify gitlab-ci jobs for deployment automation

· Configuration of gitlab-runner with the centrali repositories

Prepare Dockerfiles and docker-compose entries

#gitlab-ci #amazon #aws #amazon sqs

#python #django #django-rest #docker #docker-compose

Setting up and install remote servers to build artifacts

Funky Data - 2019 Software Developer /// Freelance

40 days as a developer at OneFlow (HP group) - Nodejs microservices 10 days at Native (Coffescript) - support on a mobile UI prototype

Senior Software Engineer /// FullStack NodeJS Dev

TDD development, full tests coverage on the API

Proj. 1 - Backend: HAPI, Mongo, MVC pattern & Jest

Proj. 1 - Devops: Docker, Circle Cl, GitHub integration

Proj. 2 - Backend: HAPI, SSR, PostgreSQL, SequelizeJS

Proj. 1 - Frontend: AngularJS 1.4 Component Based, Redux

Attended Truffle University Programme - 8 weeks remote

 Attended 2-day blockchain dev bootcamp @ King's College London Prepared own VPS Linux server for a CI/CD homebrew environment

València, Spain - Remote

Com. Valenciana - Spain

with the goal to help individuals, exchanges, mining pools, token issuers,

investment funds, governments and

cryptocurrencies and digital assets

optimally.

January 2022 - January 2023

Bit2Me is platform suite founded in 2014,

institutions to access, trade and manage

When I joined, I had the chance to work

the DevOps team was founded. Also

contributed in the Core Team.

together with the sysadmins, and with my background with software development,

and integration of high-end interactive 3D solutions in a variety of sectors.

The role in the company as a Software

March 2020 - September 2021

Moved back to València by March 2020, Got hired on Mirage - Topcon. Mirage is a

company funded in 2009, it specializes in

services related to research, development

Engineer was focused as Backend and Infrastructure.

London - UK

London - UK

September 2017 - July 2018

Vendigo is a Fintech startup which

consumers, merchants and lenders.

provides a point-of-sale financing to the

home improvement industry connecting

Joined the company at a stage when the

ecosystem. Team formed by six senior

developers, one product owner and one QA. All devs had fullstack experience with

product was getting rebuild into a NodeJS

July 2019 - March 2020

experience as a freelancer.

After the role in Vendigo (employee), decided to open a company and offer my

Prepared self repositories for a MEMP microservices stack #node #express #django-rest #docker #docker-compose

Vendigo Finance

#gitlab-ci #amazon #aws #amazon sqs

- Horizontal team in an Agile environment
- Proj. 2 Devops: Jenkins and Docker #nodejs #javascript #mongodb #postgresql #sequelize

70% backend work & 30% frontend

Enjoyed free time to travel and attend meetups and workshops

Funky Data - 2016

#nodejs #javacript #mocha #tdd #api

Software Engineer /// Freelance NodeJS Backend API development HQ MOBILE LTD

Swishd Software Developer /// Fullstack NodeJS Developer

REST API Development using TDD practices

#NodeJS #Javascript #API #development

Stack: NodeJS. Restify, Mongoose, Mocha Stack: NodeJS. Angular, Grunt Stack: Jenkins for continuous integration Infra: AWS

Commonplace.is Software Engineer /// NodeJS & REACT

#nodejs #javascript #expressjs #mocha #tdd

 Mentoring and support 3 devs: a junior FE, a mid BE and a senior iOS Core APIs with Express, Mongoose and Cloudinary Frontend with AngularJS 1x

Software Engineer /// Tech Founder

- #fullstack #nodejs #api #express #angular #mongodb
- #php #vanilla-php #rest-api-development

Production-ready for i18n

VICE Magazine

Web Developer /// Freelance

LaTiendaHome

Understand and support the CEO to define, design and shape his idea

Software Engineer /// NodeJS API dev & REACT

SpottinsStyle - Minimal Viable Product

Gallery views with advanced Javascript using CanJS and AJAX.

#python #web2py #DAL #mysql #debian-server #javascript #canjs

- #php #codeigniter #jquery #javascript
- **KM77** Software Developer /// Web Developer Fix infraestructure to achieve 99.9% uptime
- Python CLI Script as a backoffice to handle servers and db migrations Suggested and set Redmine as Ticket Tracker to apply agile Stack: PHP, Kohana, jQuery, git, MySQL, redis, python.
- #php #kohana #mysql-cluster #redis #linux-vps #python

Software Engineer /// Web Developer

AdLemons

- Implements Git and host on GitHub replacing manual FTP uploads Refactor codebase to follow MVC guidelines Implements a custom helper to handle i18n strings
- Adapt a Redmine as a Ticketing System to manage tasks Tech Stack Backend: PHP, Codelgniter, MySQL Tech Stack Frontend: jQuery, raw HTML/CSS

London - UK

July 2016 - July 2017

javascript and node.

company to offer my services as a freelance, since I needed more flexibility on times and moving from time to time to my hometown in Valencia.

Spitalfields, London - UK

Swishd was a startup which build a

platform for food and parcel deliveries,

The goal on this role was to develop and

implement features as it goes on the agile

March 2016 - July 2016

and commanded by the CTO.

Candem, London - UK

November 2015 - March 2016

Commonplace is a web platform used by

organisations, neighbourhood planning

to support and dynamise communication.

The role involved backend development, but also some frontend. Every PR must be fully tested and was automatically

local councils, property developers, housing associations, transport

groups and community groups

similar as Deliveroo.

After my role at Swishd, I openend a solo-

Infra: CIrcle-CI and AWS

Spottinstyle

 API Development using TDD practises · Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, Mongoose, React, Mocha Front: React and Selenium for E2E

Understand and project the needs with founder

Spec and design the architecture using microservices

· Integrate with 3rd Party services APIs key to the platform · Third Party: Cloudinary.io, compose.io and MailGun · Back: Multiple microservices with NodeJS/Express

· Front: Admin Backoffice with AngularJS consuming the API

· Front: Jade, Gulp, MaterializeCSS, Bower, Karma, StylusCSS

· Back: Just Vanilla-PHP, no libs nor frameworks as requirement · Front: Dashboard with CanJS / Backbone using the mentioned API

Software Engineer /// REST API PHP Development

Implement a RESTFUL API from a legacy project in Vanilla PHP / MySQL

MVC implementation using the web2py python web framework Shaping the database models using web2py's Data Abstraction Layer Use of MySQL with migrations Auth system: signup, email confirmation, login and reset password

Email Verification, Facebook Oauth & Twitter Oauth

- Developed features in the intranet as requested by the client · Technologies: PHP, Codelgniter, JQuery, git

Set replicas to MySQL from one instance to a cluster

Synced Redis to MySQL via automated daily crontasks

· Front: Implement a car comparator using raw JS and jQuery

Moved page-view inserts from MySQL to Redis

- Tech Stack Infra: SSH & Linux VPS

#javascript #node #php #codeigniter #startup #MVC #git #github

Notting Hill, London - UK July 2014 - June 2015

Spottinstyle raised seed investment in

June 2014. Since I was involved in the

project from the beggining I was proposed

to move back to London and develop the

The role was relevant for below reasons:

deployed via CI.

product.

 opportunity to design and lead a greenfield project from scratch decided to go with NodeJS all the way modern JS frontend framework (Angular) managed a team of 4 people socket.io realtime websockets delivered on time

Gandia - València, Spain November 2013 - June 2014

LaTiendaHome is an ecommerce focused

on selling mattresses and bedding clothes.

The work was concise: From the database build and implement a REST API to

provide different rest-client apps. The only requirement and somehow challenging: Just RAW PHP, not libs or frameworks

permitted.

Remote - London & València June 2013 - November 2013 In June 2013 I had to come back to València from London, due to family rreasons. Right before coming back, an exciting project was proposed to me. The founder proposal was to prototype a Fashion Social Network, with their users, galleries, tagging and comments.

The project seemed exciting, with good timing and with the opportunity to apply

knowledge on a real world scenario.

Old Street, London - UK

January 2013 - March 2013

news/politics. The contract required work on new features for the internal panell, using PHP/

focused on lifestyle, arts, culture, and

VICE.com is an alternative punk magazine,

València - Spain October 2011 - September 2012

València - Spain

Team of four employees at the time. Two developers. The role involved too improve codebase and set good practises in terms

- Codeigniter, Javascript and JQuery.
 - KM77 is a portal for the automotive industry. It lets users to visualise car models. specifications and compare every car in the market, with every specification for each car.

sponsorship in blog networks.

March 2011 - September 2011 AdLemons.com was an ad-serving platform that offers decentralised

of the deployment workflow.